Guide to the Works Progress Administration oral histories collection, 1961-1984
George Mason University Libraries
- Work Projects Administration Oral Histories
  - Lloyd, Joel, November 14, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    Puppet artist with the Marionette unit, NYC FTP.
  - Lloyd, Norman, January 5, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    Actor with the Living Newspaper unit, NYC FTP.
  - Losey, Blance Morgan, January 7, 1976 (Box 7)
    Costume designer with FTP units in Seattle and Tacoma, WA.Closed during Mr. Williams's lifetime.
  - Luening, Otto, May 10, 1982 (Box 7)
    Conductor with the Vermont FMP.
  - Lumet, Baruch, January 25, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    Father of Sidney Lumet, child actor with the Yiddish unit, NYC FTP.
  - Lynch, Dorothea, March 14, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    Administrative director with the Florida FTP.
  - McDermott, Thomas, October 23, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    Actor with the Chicago FTP.Closed during interviewee's lifetime.
  - McLean, Scott R., March 20, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    Actor with the Jacksonville and Miami FTP.Closed during interviewee's lifetime.
  - Macchiarini, Peter, February 23, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    Marionette artist with the SF FTP.Quotations must be accurate.
  - Maltz, Albert, May 27, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    Playwright whose work was produced by NYC FTP.
  - Mann, Dulce Fox, March 11, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Marshall, E.G., March 3, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Maxwell, Gilbert, March 3, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    Actor with the Atlanta FTP.
  - Meadow, Herb, August 7, 1976 (Box 7)
    Playwright and researcher with the National Play Bureau of the FTP.Closed during interviewee's lifetime.
  - Meltzer, Allan, March 18, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    Publicist with the NYC FTP.
  - Meredith, Betty Arden, July 18, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    Actress and researcher with the LA FTP; researcher with the Seattle FTP.
  - Meredith, Betty Arden see Donal Murray July 20, 1977 (Box 7)
  - Merrill, Mary, March 8, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    Costume designer with the NYC FTP.
  - Mesa, Fernando, March 15, 1977 (Box 7)
    Stage manager with the Tampa FTP.Closed during interviewee's lifetime.
  - Meyer, Harriet B., August 20, 1975 (Box 7)
    Administrator with the Research Bureau, NYC FTP.This is an untaped interview.
  - Miller, Carl, May 13, 1982 (Box 7)
    Staff member with the Educational Division, NYC FTP.
  - Miller, J. Howard, January 5, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    Administrative director with the West Coast units of FTP; deputy National Director of FTP.
  - Miller J. Howard, October 18, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Miller J. Howard, June 1, 1979 (Box 7)
  - Monroe, Charles, November 9, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    Member of the Seattle Negro Repertory Theatre in the 1930s.Closed to any government agency.
  - Morcom, James S., May 10, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    Set designer with the NYC FTP.
  - Morris, Lawrence S., January 1977 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    Worked with the NYC FTP. This is an untaped interview.
  - Morrow, Fred (Box 7, Folder 28)
    Director with the FTP in the South; later with the Detroit FTP.
  - Moss, Carlton, August 6, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Theatrical director with the Negro unit, NYC FTP.
  - Murray, Donald, July 20, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Actor, director, writer with the Southwest Experimental unit of the LA FTP.
  - Muse, Clarence, January 4, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Director with the Negro unit, LA FTP.
  - Nadel, Sue Ramos, October 23, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Dancer with the NYC FTP.
  - Norford, George T., October 25, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    Writer and playwright who submitted work to the Negro unit, NYC FTP.This is an untaped interview.
  - Norvelle, Lee R., July 11,1979 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    Director with the Indiana FTP.
  - Ottenheimer, Albert M., January 10, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    Actor with the Seattle FTP.
  - Page, Ruth, April 24, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    Dancer and choreographer with the Chicago FTP.
  - Perlowin, Paula Bass see S.R. Nadel October 23, 1977 (Box 8)
  - Peterson, Arthur, July 22, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Pezman, Theodore, October 26, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    Writer with the Southwest Experimental unit of the LA FTP.
  - Phelps, Eleanor, December 13, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    Actress and student of Hallie Flanagan at Vassar College.This is an untaped interview.
  - Phillips, Wendell, May 27, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    Actor; director with Suitcase Theatre; assistant director with the Classical unit, NYC FTP.
  - Pierce, Evelyn, November 10, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    Director of casting with the Talent Bureau, NYC FTP.Closed pending release.
  - Pinska, Klarna, February 24, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Pollock, Max, January 8, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    Director of the Vaudeville productions, LA FTP.
  - Ponch, Martin with Nancy Ponch, May 26, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    Actor in Yiddish theater and New York University repertory groups during the FTP era.
  - Poole, Valter, April 28, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    Conductor with the Michigan WPA Symphony Orchestra.
  - Porter, Don, January 8, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    Actor with the LA and Portland (OR) FTP units.This is an untaped interview.
  - Price, Herbert, July 31, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    With the WPA program in Connecticut; also with the CCC; founded the Plymouth Playhouse; worked briefly on the set of Faustus.
  - Randolph, John, May 28, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    Actor with the Children's unit, NYC FTP.
  - Rather, Lois Rodecap, August 24, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    Researcher of the Chinese theater, Research Department, SF FTP.
  - Rauch, Lillian Shapero, June 10, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    Choreographer with the Yiddish unit, NYC FTP.Closed during interviewee's lifetime.
  - Reese, Amos, July 20, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    Radio script writer, Radio Division, NYC FTP.This is an untaped interview.
  - Refregier, Anton, January 2, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    Artist, muralist with the FAP in NY, NJ, and CA.Permission of interviewer required for publication.
  - Reich, Molka, March 19, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    Actress and director with the marionette unit of the Miami FTP.
  - Rella, Ettore, November 13, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    Playwright in New York and San Francisco; write with the FWP.
  - Rhodes, Irwin, February 26, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    Administrator and legal counsel for the National Service Bureau, FTP.
  - Rhodes, Irwin, May 10, 1977 (Box 8)
  - Rich, Shirley, November 9, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    Hallie Flanagan's assistant who collected Flanagan's papers which were donated to the Theatre Collection, New York Public Library.
  - Roberts, Gordon, October 30, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Actor with the Cleveland (OH) FTP.
  - Robinson, Earl, August 1976 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    Composer for various productions, NYC FTP.
  - Robson, William N., September 13, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    Writer and director with the Radio Division, NYC FTP.
  - Romano, Amelia, March 4, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    Actress with the NYC FTP.
  - Rome, Harold, March 13, 1980 (Box 9)
    Lyricist who wrote the words for "Papa's Got a Job" for Sing For Your Supper under the pseudonym of Hector Troy.This is an untaped interview.
  - Rosten, Norman, November 14, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    Playwright, play reader with the Playwriting Bureau, NYC FTP.Prior consent required for publication.
  - Rubenstein, Lewis, December 14, 1978 (Box 9)
    Muralist with the Massachusetts and New York FAP.Permission of interviewer required for publication.
  - Russak, Ben, February 19, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    Administrator, Playwriting Bureau, FTP.Permission of interviewee required; copyright conditions.
  - Saul, Oscar, June 2, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    Playwright in NYC whose works were produced by FTP.This is an untaped interview.
  - Saunders, Wardell, October 27, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    Actor with the Negro unit, NYC FTP. This is an untaped interview.
  - Savage, George, January 6, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    Playwright and director with the Seattle FTP.Closed during Guy Williams's lifetime.
  - Saxe, Al, March 18, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    Director with the Experimental unit, NYC FTP.Closed pending release.
  - Schenker, Augusta Weissberger, March 2, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    Administrative assistant with the Negro and Classical units, NYC FTP.
  - Schnitzer, Marcella Cisney, November 17, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    Actress with the Radio Division, NYC FTP.
  - Schnitzer, Robert, November 17, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    Administrator, Delaware FTP; with FTP national office, Washington, DC; with the San Francisco World's Fair, 1939.
  - Schnitzer, Robert, November 7, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Schoolman, Mary Sackler, June 22, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    Administrative assistant to Philip Barber, NYC FTP. Closed during interviewee's lifetime.
  - Schrager, Philip, February 28, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    Assistant stage manager with the Living Newspaper unit, NYC FTP.
  - Schulman, Rose, April 15, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    Administrative assistant to Jasper Deeter, first director of the Pennsylvania/New Jersey FTP.
  - Schulman, Sol, January 22, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    Audience member, NYC FTP productions.
  - Schuman, William, May 3, 1982 (Box 9)
    Composer, NYC FMP.
  - Scooler, Zvee, April 19, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    Director of the Anglo-Jewish unit, NYC FTP.
  - Scott, Isabel, March 15, 1977 (Box 9)
    Worked with Children's and Vaudeville units, Miami and Tampa FTP. Closed during Fernando Mesa's lifetime.
  - Shaw, Zachary, August 27, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    Puppeteer with the Marionette unit, NYC FTP.
  - Sherman, Hiram, April 18, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    Actor with the Classical unit, NYC FTP.
  - Sherman, Vincent, January 7, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    Writer and playwright in NYC at the time of the FTP. This is an untaped interview.
  - Shibley, Eleanor Scherr, August 5, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    Actress, NYC FTP.
  - Shibley, Eleanor Scherr, September 22, 1976 (Box 9)
  - Shohet, Max, January 26, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    Publicist, NYC FTP.
  - Shrewsbury, Robert, June 11, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    Actor with the Chicago, Peoria, and Miami FTP; worked with sets and costumes in Chicago.
  - Sidney, P. Jay, October 25, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    Actor with the Children's and Negro units, NYC FTP. Closed pending release.
  - Siegal, Fritz, April 27, 1982 (Box 9)
    Concertmaster with the FMP Illinois Symphony.
  - Siegmeister, Elie, May 8, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    Composer with the NYC FTP; wrote the score for FTP's Created Equal.
  - Silvera, John, July 11, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    Publicist with the Negro unit, NYC FTP.
  - Simon, Louis, October 25, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    Administrative director, NJ FTP; director of repertory unit, Roslyn, NY FTP. Written permission of interviewee required for publication.
  - Sklar, George, January 2, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    Playwright in NYC whose work was produced by the FTP. Permission to quote required by interviewee.
  - Slane, Michael Andrew May/June 1979 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    Director, Denver FTP.
  - Smith, Carlton Sprague, April 8, 1982 (Box 10)
    Worked with Composers's Forum and Copying Project of the FMP.
  - Sokolow, Anna, November 9, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    Choreographer, NYC FTP. This is an untaped interview.
  - Solman, Joseph, January 1975 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    Artist, NY FAP. Permission of interviewer required for publication.
  - Sour, Robert, October 31, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    Songwriter whose works were performed by NYC FTP.
  - Spayde, Sydney H., July 19, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    Administrator with Iowa FTP; assistant to E.C. Mabie, regional director for the Midwest FTP.
  - Staton, Joseph, January 7, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Stavis, Barrie, November 8, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    Playwright whose work was produced by the FTP.
  - Stone, Gene, July 21, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    Composer and arranger with the Vaudeville unit, LA FTP.
  - Stover, Frederick, June 8, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    Set designer, LA FTP.
  - Strassberg, Maurice, January 24, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    Actor with the Anglo-Jewish unit, NYC FTP. Closed pending release.
  - Stuckmann, Eugene, February 23, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    Actor with the New Hampshire FTP. Closed pending release.
  - Suib, Leonard, April 19, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    Puppeteer in NYC familiar with the Marionette and Children's units, NYC FTP.
  - Sundgaard, Arnold, September 5, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    Playwright in Chicago whose work was produced by the FTP.
  - Talbot, Clarence, July 21, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    Administrator, director, actor, and playwright involved with the Seattle and Tacoma FTP, and the Des Moines FTP.
  - Teichmann, Howard, April 18, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    Stage Manager with the Mercury Theatre, New York.
  - Thomas, Ted, October 19, 1977 (Box 10)
    Theatrical director with the Classical unit, NYC FTP. Closed pending release.
  - Thomson, Virgil, November 5, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    Musical director with the Negro and Classical units, NYC FTP.
  - Thomson, Virgil, May 11, 1982 (Box 10)
    Musical director with the Negro and Classical units. NYC FTP.
  - Tilton, Mary Seek, January 24, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    Worked with the National Youth Administration and the WPA in Iowa. Closed pending release.
  - Tyler, Converse, December 15, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    Administrator, National Play Bureau, NYC FTP.
  - Valiant, Margaret, April 14, 1979 (Box 10)
    Worked with the Resettlement Administration.
  - Velie, Jay, May 24, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    Actor with the Roslyn, NY FTP.
  - Wallace, Lea, June 13, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    Dancer with Tamiris's group, Dance Project, NYC FTP.
  - Ward, Theodore April 7-8, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    Playwright based in Chicago whose works were produced by the FTP. Permission to quote over 100 words required.
  - Ward, Theodore April 12, 1974, August 13, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    Playwright based in Chicago whose works were produced by the FTP.
  - Warde, Frances, January 8, 1976 (Box 11)
    Actress with the Vaudeville unit, LA FTP.
  - Wasserman, Dale, January 23, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Stage manager, actor, and lighting technician with the LA FTP.
  - Wasserman, Dale, May 30, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    Stage manager, actor, and lighting technician, LA FTP.
  - Weisberg, Sara Thomas, April 6, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Administrator, Atlanta FTP.
  - Weissberger, Arnold, April 19, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    Lawyer who represented Orson Welles and John Houseman.
  - Welles, Halsted, November 17, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    Director with the NYC FTP.
  - White, Charles, December 29, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    Muralist with the Illinois FAP. Permission needed to quote over 100 words.
  - Whiteside, Duncan, August 13, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    Lighting director and technician with the Chicago FTP.
  - Wilder, Grace, July 15, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    Administrator with the Marionette unit of the NYC FTP.
  - Wilkes, Nathan, November 28, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    Puppeteer and lighting designer with the Marionette unit, NYC FTP.
  - Williams, Guy, January 6, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    Theatrical director with the Seattle FTP. Closed during Mr. Williams's lifetime.
  - Williams, Guy, January 7, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Williams, Jay, September 8, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    Stage manager with the Children's theater, NYC FTP.
  - Wilson, Ellis, February 25, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    Artist with the Illinois and New York FAP.
  - Wilson, Jack, July 19, 1977 (Box 11)
    Research with the San Francisco Theatre History project; actor in several SF FTP productions.
  - Yasko, Karel, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    Worked with the GSA; recovered many FAP works and murals.